VATSAL JOSHI

6355352285

 $joshivatsal 256@gmail.com \diamond https://www.linkedin.com/in/vatsal-joshi-91b148239/ \diamond https://github.com/vatsaljoshi22/linkedin.com/in/vatsal-joshi-91b148239/ \diamond https://github.com/vatsaljoshi22/linkedin.com/in/vatsal-joshi-91b148239/ \diamond https://github.com/vatsaljoshi22/linkedin.com/in/vatsal-joshi-91b148239/ \diamond https://github.com/vatsaljoshi-91b148239/ \diamond https://github.com/vatsaljoshi-91b148240/ \diamond https://github.com/va$

OBJECTIVE

My name is Vatsal Joshi and I am a graduate of Computer Science Engineering from Parul University. In addition to my academic qualifications, I have acquired hands-on experience as a front-end developer through four months of training and a three-month internship at Webbrains Technology. Throughout these experiences, I have actively contributed to various projects and honed my skills in front-end technologies such as JavaScript and React.js..

EDUCATION

10th, M.N.J Patel	2017
12th, Ashadeep Science	2019
Bachelor of Computer Science, Parul University	2019 - 2023

SKILLS

 ${\bf Technical\ Skills} \qquad {\bf Reactjs,\ JavaScript,\ Redux,\ HTML,\ CSS,\ Bootstrap.}$

Soft Skills Node.js, Tailwindcss, Figma.

EXPERIENCE

Front end Developer Webbrains Technology

April 2023 - Jan2024

Vadodara, Gujarat

- I have a strong knowledge of JavaScript concepts and gained hands-on experience in ReactJS through various projects.
- I can solve many problems related to HTML and JavaScript tasks, and then utilize the React.JS framework to make websites more efficient. I have hands-on experience completing many projects utilizing these skills.
- I also created a weather app, to-do list, and expense tracker. I also utilized Axio for API calls and learned various methods.

.Net developer

Jan 2023 - Feb 2023

Pintionclickhelthcare

Vadodara, Gujarat

- I have completed my one-month training.NET development.
- I am interested in learning how to design and maintain software and applications using Microsoft.NET framework.

PROJECTS

Freshmart. This project will be created using JavaScript and ReactJS. Here, I will be using Axios and Redux, and also adding functionality to the cart. After that, I will use Tailwind CSS to add more styling to this website and implement the 'add to cart' functionality.

BOXICHAMPWeb-Page. The homepage of BOXICHAMP features a dynamic design that promotes an immersive experience for users. By utilizing captivating imagery, bold fonts, and interactive elements, the page effectively conveys the organization's mission, lessons, and unique experience. The user-friendly navigation ensures that visitors can easily explore the various aspects of the organization and make informed decisions about their participation.

Covid-19 Statistics website. This webpage displays COVID-19 statistics for multiple countries and specific dates. In this project, I will also be using the Axios library to call an AI. This is a real-world project that displays COVID-19 cases.

News Web App. In this news website, I will use Axios to call the API in object form. Then, I will use React and Bootstrap to style the website. Help me get daily news.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• I'm actively involved in EDM music production, creating and producing tracks. I also enjoy vlogging to share my experiences and connect with an audience. Additionally, I engage in gaming streaming, combining my love for video games with community interaction. These activities reflect my diverse interests and showcase my creativity and communication skills

CERTIFICATE

- Udemy (01/2020-08/2020) Web developer bootcamp.
- \bullet WebTech- Front-end developer.